A Guide to the Papers of Ambrose Bierce, 1842-1914
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- General Correspondence
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC, to Harriet Hershberg, San Francisco CA 1900 JAN 21, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce tells her that "it is not worthwhile to love you anymore, for I shall never see you again" even if she should visit Pittsburgh because the coal smoke from the railway engines makes him very ill and there is little else in Pittsburgh. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [May Elizabeth] McAlister 1900 FEB 10, ALS. 4 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC, to Harriet Hershberg, San Francisco CA 1900 MAR 24, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Asks about the family and when she will be able to visit her sister Nettie in Pittsburgh and him in Washington [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC, to Harriet Hershberg, San Francisco CA 1900 MAY 12, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce declares that if he shall ever see those whom he loves again he will have to do the traveling "to the imminent destruction of my lungs" and wishes her "as much happiness as I can make up my mind that you ought to have in my absence." [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1900 JUN 8, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to [May Elizabeth] McAlister 1900 JUN 17, ALS. 4 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to "Friend of Former Days" [Ambrose Bierce] 1900 AUG 1, ALS. 2 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1900 AUG 8, ALS. 5 p. (Box 4)
    Bierce deals with a coolness or "defection" growing out of their joint venture in publishing Black Beetles. Bierce also refuses to jointly republish The Monk because their business relationship was "the rock that wrecked our friendship." [#5992-a]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC, to Harriet Hershberg, San Francisco CA 1900 AUG 8, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce hopes to see her in Washington before she leaves on her trip to Europe with her sister Nettie and offers to show her the capital [#5992-j]
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to "My dear Friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1900 AUG 13, ALS. 3 p. (Box 4)
    [#5992- a]
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to [May Elizabeth] McAlister 1900 AUG 21, ALS. 3 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to "My dear friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1900 AUG 24, ALS. 4 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to "My blessed Friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1900 AUG 27, ALS. 2 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1900 SEP 4, ALS. 2 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to "My dear Friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1900 SEP 14, ALS. 3 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to [May Elizabeth] McAlister 1900 SEP 16, ALS. 4 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to "My dear Friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1900 OCT 29, ALS. 3 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1900 NOV 2, ALS. 7 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC, to Harriet Hershberg, Pittsburgh PA 1900 DEC 1, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Having just returned from an unpleasant fortnight in New York, Bierce hopes that Hattie will be able to visit him in Washington, although he would be willing to return to New York to see her. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to "Dear Friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1900 DEC 4, ALS. 6 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Carroll [M.] Carrington 1900 DEC 12, ALS. 4 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC, to Harriet Hershberg, Pittsburgh PA 1900 DEC 27, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 4)
    Bierce looks forward to seeing Harriet in a few days and describes his Christmas Day activities. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Carroll M.] Carrington [ca. 1900], ALS. 2 p. (Box 4)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to "My dear Friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1901 JAN 13, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC, to Harriet Hershberg, Pittsburgh PA 1901 FEB 8, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 5)
    Bierce assures her that he is not angry that she won't be coming to Washington because "I have lived long enough to learn that a woman's promise is merely the expression of a mood - and woman's moods do not last long." [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC, to Harriet Hershberg, New York City [1901 FEB 20], ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 5)
    Bierce is glad that Hattie had a good time in Washington during her visit and that she is enjoying New York City as well but does not plan to see her in New York. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to "My dear friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1901 FEB 20, ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to "Betty" [May Elizabeth McAlister] 1901 FEB 23, ALS. 4 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to "My dear Friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1901 MAR 18, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to "My dear friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1901 APR 15, ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to "My dearest Friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1901 MAY 18, ALS. 16 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to "Betty" [May Elizabeth McAlister] 1901 JAN 10, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC, to Harriet Hershberg, Pittsburgh PA 1901 JUN 10, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 5)
    Bierce thanks her for her expression of sympathy and mentions that his daughter is visiting with him. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington DC, to Harriet Hershberg, Pittsburgh PA 1901 JUL 10, TLS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 5)
    Bierce writes that he hopes her reasons for staying in the East so long is due to having such a good time and not the matchmaking attempts of Sally and Nettie, and he also touts his typewriting ability "I have one great qualification: I can hold my tongue, though sometimes both hands are required to do the job." [#5992-j]
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to "Betty" [May Elizabeth McAlister] 1901 JUL 21, TLS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from [G.] A. Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1901 DEC 20, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Dr. Robertson 1902 JAN 17, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from [G.] A. Danziger to "My dear friend" [Bierce] 1902 FEB 2, ALS. 5 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to "My dear Friend" [Ambrose Bierce], including several poems [1902 MAR 23], ALS. 7 p. (Box 5)
    - Enclosure: bill of sale for rights to "The Monk and the Hangman's Daughter" 1902 MAR 23, ADS. 1 p.
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1902 APR 17, ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to "My dear friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1902 JUL 17, ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1902 JUL 19, TLS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1902 JUL 20, ALS. 4 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [G.A.] Danziger 1902 JUL 24, TLS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1902 JUL 26, ALS. 4 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to Betty [May Elizabeth McAlister] 1902 AUG 8, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from "Brosia" [Ambrose Bierce] to Betty [May Elizabeth McAlister] 1902 AUG 10, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to [May Elizabeth McAlister] 1902 DEC 15, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1903 MAR 28, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1903 APR 3, ALS. 4 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to "My dear Friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1903 APR 14, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to "my dear friend" [Ambrose Bierce] 1903 MAY 10, ALS. 5 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Adolphe Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce 1903 AUG 2, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Walter] Neale [of Neale Publishing Co.] 1903 AUG 21, ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
    [#5992-g]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Aurora, WV, to Harriet Hershberg, Pittsburgh PA 1903 SEP 27, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
    Having received her note about her impending marriage, Bierce writes, "It is pleasant to know that you still live, though about to die - I mean marry and live in Philadelphia. I approve the marriage, but Philadelphia! - that is going too far" and asks for news of everyone. [#5992-j]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mr. Mackay 1904 FEB 19, ALsS. 1p. each. (Box 5)
    2 letters sent to different addresses. [#5992]
    - Enclosure: Photograph of Ambrose Bierce. 1896, Pntd
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Betty [May Elizabeth McAlister] 1904 MAY 6, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [John O'Hara] Cosgrave 1905 MAR 11, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mr. Mackay 1905 MAY 2, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [John O'Hara] Cosgrave 1905 OCT 20, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from [John O'Hara Cosgrave] to Ambrose Bierce 1905 NOV 17, TL. 3 p. (Box 5)
    - Enclosure: From "Musical Leader" 1905 SEP 21, Clipping
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [John O'Hara] Cosgrave 1905 NOV 19, ALS. 11 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [John O'Hara] Cosgrave 1906 JAN 28, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Lella Cotton [1906 MAY 14], L copy. 1 p. (Box 5)
    Original in Shapes of Clay[Barrett PS 1097.S34 1903] [ #5992-f]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [John O'Hara] Cosgrave 1906 JUL 12, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [John O'Hara] Cosgrave 1906 AUG 20, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [John O'Hara] Cosgrave 1906 AUG 29, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Walter] Neale [of Neale Publishing Co.] 1906 OCT 17, ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [John O'Hara] Cosgrave 1906 NOV 8, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from [John O'Hara Cosgrave] to Ambrose Bierce 1906 NOV 14, TL. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [John O'Hara] Cosgrave 1906 NOV 23, ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from [John O'Hara Cosgrave]to Ambrose Bierce 1906 NOV 26, TL. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mr. Howes 1907 APR 24, ALS. 4 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from [Ambrose Bierce] to his daughter, Helen D. Cowden 1907 NOV 14, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. and transcript (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Miss G.A. Higham (of the Neale Publishing Company), 1 p. 1908 APR 17, TLS (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Miss G.A. Higham (of the Neale Publishing Company) 1908 APR 17, TLS. 1 p. carbon copy (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [S.O.] Howes 1908 MAY 11, TLS. 3 p. (Box 5)
    An important letter concerning the material later used in Shapes of Clay and the Collected Works, which Howes was then compiling. Howes wishes to publish it all in two volumes; Bierce replies that Howes has a moral right, by agreement, to publish only one and that Bierce should have surplus material for a volume of essays promised for the Collected Works. [#5992-f]
  - Letter from [Ambrose Bierce] to his daughter, Mrs. H.D. Cowden 1908 JUN 24, ALS. 5 p. w/ env. and transcript (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [ ? ] 1908 OCT 9, ALSfrag. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mr. Wilstach 1908 DEC 5, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
    The recipient may be Frank Jenners Wilstach; the reference to "Wilstachian thinglets" may be FJW's A Dictionary of Similes(Little, Brown & Co., Boston, 1916) [#5992-h]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Miss Manning 1908 DEC 18, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from "Pops" [Ambrose Bierce] to "Bib" 1909 JAN 6, ALS. 3 p. w/ transcript (Box 5)
  - Letter from Stock certificate for 100 shares of The Neale Publishing Company 1909 JAN 9, DS. 2 p. (Box 5)
    Cancellation noted, 1913 SEP 3, [upon receipt of 1913 AUG 29 transfer of title to Carrie J. Christiansen] [#5992-g]
  - Letter from Proxy for The Neale Publishing Company stockholders' meeting (signed by Ambrose Bierce and witnessed by Carrie J. Christiansen) 1909 MAR 3, DS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [May Elizabeth McAlister] 1909 SEP 12, Frag (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, The Army & Navy Club, Washington, D.C., to "My dear Madam" 1909 OCT 27, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
    Bierce returns her "excellent verses" which she had enclosed in a letter to him under the misunderstanding that he had some editorial connection with Cosmopolitan Magazine. [#5992-n]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to J[ack] S. Dunnigan 1910 JUN 1, ALS. 2 p. w/ env. (Box 5)
    [#5992-e]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Jack S. Dunnigan 1910 JUL 21, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 5)
    [#5992-d]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Walter] Neale [of Neale Publishing Co.] 1910 DEC 26, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington, D.C., to "Dear Neale" [Walter Neale] 1911 JAN 29, ALS. 3 p. w/ transcript (Box 5)
    Bierce returns the proofs of volume seven of The Devil's Dictionary, approves of Neale's announcement of books undertaken in 1910, "A pretty ambitious project. They go a long way toward making my dream come true, namely, that you are to be the foremost publisher in America," and rejoices that he has only three and a half volumes of page proofs yet to read, with a newsclipping about the growth of thin paper used in bookmaking.
    Tipped in with a typed transcript in a copy of In the Midst of Life by Ambrose Bierce (1898) [#5992-q]
  - Letter from Receipt for 100 shares [of The Neale Publishing Company] to Ambrose Bierce (signed by Ambrose Bierce) 1911 FEB 10, DS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from [Ambrose Bierce] to his daughter, Mrs. Helen D. Cowden 1911 FEB 19, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Hudson Maxim to Ambrose Bierce 1911 MAR 11, TLS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington, D.C. to publisher [Walter] Neale 1911 APR 11, TLS. 1 p. (Box 5)
    Bierce quotes a long excerpt from a letter to him from S.O. Howe, the editor of his book, The Shadow on the Dial and Other Essays, published in San Francisco by A.M. Robertson in 1909, which makes arrangements for transferring the copyright for The Shadow on the Dial. Bierce also refers to waiting for a few page proofs. [#5992-r]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Walter] Neale [of Neale Publishing Co.] 1911 JUN 7, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
    Bierce takes issue with Neale in his refusal to serve on a jury with a Negro and agreeing with him in his opposition to the Fifteenth Amendment, "but are you sure that the Judge will not punish you for contempt, seeing in your protest only an advertisement of your book and business?..." [#5992]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Walter] Neale [of Neale Publishing Co.] 1911 JUL 17, ALS. 4 p. w/ transcript. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Charles Dexter Allen 1911 SEP 27, L copy. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce, Washington, to [Walter] Neale 1911 OCT 5, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
    Bierce writes to his friend, eventual biographer, and publisher of The Collected Works of Ambrose Bierce, Walter Neale, thanking him for his explanation about Kaufman and his copyright lawyer, and mentioning the anger of the artist Miss Campbell over Neale's refusal to see her and the work she had done at his suggestion, "being an artist and a woman, she is naturally a bit sensitive. May I say anything to comfort her?" [#5992-l]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Walter] Neale [of Neale Publishing Co.] 1911 OCT 10, ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Walter] Neale [of Neale Publishing Co.] 1911 OCT 11, TLS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Charles Dexter Allen 1911 OCT 25, L copy. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from A[mbrose]; B[ierce] to Walter Neale [1911 DEC 28], APCS (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Maj. H.H. Sargent 1912 MAY 14, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 5)
    [#5992-c]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Mrs. Beckman ?] 1912 AUG 29, ALS frag. p.3 only (Box 5)
    Bierce writes in this partial letter, "I am not a 'free agent' and can now (as my time is short) hope to see only a few even of those whom I most wish to see." He also warns that Sacramento "is bad for the heart - it used to be bad for mine." [#5992-k]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Ruth Robertson 1912 SEP 24, ALS. 3 p. w/ env. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Proxy for The Neale Publishing Company stockholders' meeting (signed by Ambrose Bierce and witnessed by Carrie J. Christiansen) 1912 DEC 26, DS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to Mrs. Beckman 1912, ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
    Bierce apologizes for not being at home when Mrs. Beckman and Mrs. Wright came to call and refers to her health, "I fancy that good big heart of yours is not going to fail you. It has never failed those who love you - for example." [#5992-k]
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Walter] Neale [of Neale Publishing Co.] 1913 JAN 3, ALS. 4 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [Walter] Neale [of Neale Publishing Co.] 1913 JAN 22, ALS. 3 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from [Ambrose Bierce] to his daughter, Mrs. Helen D. Cowden 1913 MAY 1, ALS. 1 p. w/ env. (Box 5)
    - Enclosure: Miss Shamp to Ambrose Bierce re: the death of her uncle, George Fee n.d., ALS, 2 p.
  - Letter from William H. Mead to George J. Beyer, with ANS reply, 1 p. 1915 JUL 28, TLS (Box 5)
    [#5992- f]
  - Letter from [Helen D. Bierce Cowden] to Messrs. Willie and Inglis 1916 MAY 23, TL. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce to [Edward L.G.] Steele n.y. NOV 18, ALS. 4 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to [?] n.y. [Christmas], ALS frag (Box 5)
    Bierce mentions his poor health since midsummer and looks forward to the visit of his friends. [#5992-k]
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce, Auburn, to [Edward L.G.] Steele "Sunday," n.d., ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce, Auburn, to [Edward L.G.] Steele "Tuesday," n.d., ALS. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from A[mbrose] G. Bierce, [San Francisco], to [Edward L.G.] Steele "Tuesday," n.d., ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from G.A. D[anziger] to [Ambrose] Bierce n.d., ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger, New York, to "My dear friend" [Ambrose Bierce] "Friday," n.d., ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce n.d., ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce n.d., ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from [G.A.] Danziger to [Ambrose] Bierce n.d., ALS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Letter from G.A. Danziger to "My dear friend" [Ambrose Bierce] n.d., ALS. 1 p (Box 5)
    TL copy, n.y. SEP 18 S.L. Clemens [Mark Twain] to [Edward Steele], 1 p. [#5992-f] [#5992-a]
- Manuscripts and Miscellaneous Papers
  - "Ambrose Bierce at Home," by his daughter, Helen Bierce (Cowden) No Date, TM. 11 p. [publ. in American Mercury, vol. 30, p.453-8] (Box 5)
  - Poem, "My speech is but a tear," by Gustav Adolpf Danziger No Date, AMS. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Poem, "The Empty Heart," by Adolphe Danziger No Date, TM. 1 p. (Box 5)
  - Poem, "Does Civilization Civilize? / Yes and No / A parody - Go as you please," by [A.G. Danziger] No Date, AM. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Poems "Presentiment" and Not Guilty," inscribed to Betty May McAlister (Snyder) [ 1899 ], Pntd. 2 p. (Box 5)
  - Calling cards: Mollie E. Day, Mr. & Mrs. Ambrose Bierce, Mrs. Ambrose Bierce, and Leigh Bierce No Date, Pntd. 6 items (Box 5)
  - Letter from 1918-1958, Pntd. Newsclippings, 4 items (Box 5)
  - "Picture from the Past / Wright's Station" No Date, (1904 photograph and caption) (Box 5)
    [publ. in Times Observer]
  - "Ambrose Bierce's daughter" (photograph and caption) and "Famous father alive, believes woman who is to search Mexico" 1918 DEC 6 (Box 5)
    [publ. in The Bulletin, San Francisco]
  - "Old letters reveal life views of Bierce, Noted writer shown in his varied moods" 1922 NOV 6 (Box 5)
    [publ. in The San Francisco Examiner]
  - " 'Just keep faith' - she says"(incl. photo of Mrs. May Snyder) 1954 OCT 12 (Box 5)
    [publ. in Los Gatos Daily Times]
  - Letter from Funeral notice for May Elizabeth Snyder 1958 AUG 5, Pntd (Box 5)
  - Envelope from Ambrose Bierce addressed to George Sterling 1905 MAR 13, frag. (Box 5)
  - Letter from Ambrose Bierce to "My Dear Reagles" 1904 Feb 26, ALS. 2 p on 1 l. (Box 5)
    [5992-s]
- A Lost Chapter in the Career of Ambrose Bierce, the Black Hills Correspondence
  - Volume I
    - "Copy of Resolutions passed by the Executive Committee of the Black Hills Placer Mining Co." 1880 JUL 7, AMS. 3 p., w/ dkt (Box 6)
      p. i
    - "Copy of a Resolution passed by the Executive Committee of The Black Hills Placer Mining Company." 1880 JUL 7, AMS. 2 p, w/ dkt. (Box 6)
      p. ii
    - A. G. Bierce,Gen.Spt., Rockerville, D[akota] T[erritory], to Jno. McGinnis Jr., Vice President, Black Hills Placer Mining Company. 1880 JUL 15, ALS. 5 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 1-5
    - "Agreement and Contract of Sale and Conveyance made and entered into at Deadwood, D[akota]; T[erritory]... between J. M. West... and the Black Hills Placer Mining Company... " (drafted by Bierce) 1880 JUL, AM. 8 p., incl. dkt (copy) (Box 6)
      p. 5a
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to Mr. McGinnis. 1880 JUL 15, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 9 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 6-15
      note: p. 9 omitted in numbering error in page sequence: correct sequence is pages 13, 15, 14.
    - H. Kaufman, San Francisco, to "My dear Bierce." 1880 JUN 24, ALS. 4 p. (Box 6)
      p. 15.a
    - H. Kaufman, San F[rancis]co, to "My dear Bierce." 1880 JUL 15, ALS. 6 p. (Box 6)
      p. 15.b
      - Babcock & Campbell, Rockerville, D[akota]; T[erritory], to Messrs. Wilsic, Bierce, and Shaler, Black Hills P[lacer]; M[ining] Co. 1880 JUL 7, - insert. ALS. 1 p., w/ dkt (Box 6)
    - A. G. Bierce, General Agent, to B. G. Caulfield. n.y. JUL 18, ALS. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 16
    - A. G. Bierce to "My Dear Eaton." n.y. JUL 18, ALS. 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 17-19
      note: p. 20 omitted in numbering
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to Mr. McGinnis. 1880 JUL 20, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 21
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to Mr. McGinnis. 1880 JUL 22, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 22-24
    - Statement of account, A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, in account with John McGinnis, Jr. 1880 JUN-JUL, AD. 2 p., w/ dkt (Box 6)
      p. 24.a
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to Mr. McGinnis. 1880 JUL 23, ALS (marked "personal" in pencil.) 5 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 25-29
    - H. Kaufman, San F[rancis]co, to "My dear Bierce." 1880 JUL 23, ALS. 4 p. (Box 6)
      p. 29.a
    - H. Kaufman, S[an]; F[rancis]co, to "My dear Bierce." 1880 JUL 24, ALS. 4 p. (Box 6)
      p. 29.b
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to M. C. Thum. 1880 JUL 24, ALS. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 30
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to Mr. McGinnis. 1880 JUL 24, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 4 p. letterpress copy. (Box 6)
      p. 31-34
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, Dakota, to Mr. Perkins. 1880 JUL 25, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 35-37
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, to Mr. McGinnis. 1880 JUL 23, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 4 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 38-41
      - Promissory note / employment contract, A. G. Bierce, General Agent, Black Hills Placer Mining Co., to W. H. Beedle. 1880 JUL 27, ADS. 1 p., w/ dkt. (Box 6)
        - insert:
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to [M. C.] Thum. 1800 AUG 3, ALS. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 42
    - H. Kaufman, San Francisco, to "My dear Bierce." 1880 AUG 3, ALS. 4 p. (Box 6)
      p. 42.a
    - A. G. Bierce, General Agent, Black Hills Placer Mining Company, Rockerville, D.T., to D. McLaughlin 1880 AUG 3, ALS. 1 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 43
    - A. G. Bierce, Rockerville, D.T., to Mr. McGinnis. 1880 AUG 6, ALS. (marked "personal" in pencil.) 3 p. letterpress copy (Box 6)
      p. 44-46
    - omitted in numbering (Box 6)
      p. 47